BO LAN

356 Princeton St., East Boston, MA, 02128; 857-350-7615 lanbo64@gmail.com

SUMMARY:

Experiences in web server management, coding free software, and 3D designing would bring an innovative and productive work environment. Leadership, communication, and language skills should be great for every communication position. Accounting experience and financial skills would provide a benefit for management of costs, investments, and other financial transactions.

EDUCATION:

Master of Science in Organizational Leadership (GPA 3.19)

May 2014

Northeastern University, Boston, MA

Certified General Accountant Students Program

September 2008 - Present

Beijing Branch of Certified General Accountants Association of Canada, Beijing, China

Bachelor of Management in Financial Management (GPA 3.2)

May 2011

Accounting School, Huanghe Science and Technology College, Zhengzhou, Henan, China

SKILLS:

Computer Design Skills: Libreoffice, LATEX, Gimp, Inkscape, Kdenlive Video Editor, Audacity Audio Editor, Blender 3D, Emacs Text Editor, Scribus

Programming: C/C++, Python, CSS, HTML, Javascript, SQL Database, GTK+, Google App Engine, Blender Game Engine, OGRE 3D Engine.

Operating Systems: GNU/Linux

Accounting & Finance: GAAP, Financial Statements, Journal Entries, Contribution Margin & Cost Management, Auditing & Working Paper, Consolidated financial statements, Investment Analysis

Accounting & Auditing Softwares: GnuCash, SAGE Accpac, Caseware: Working Paper, Yongyou U8 Solution

Languages: English, Mandarin, Cantonese

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES:

Nanning Bicycle Network Company- http://www.nnzxc.com

Co-founder, Organizer, Web manager

Nanning, Guangxi, China
October 2003 - September 2011

- Managed, operated, and promoted a commercial website which sells bikes. This website is used PHP, MySql, and the Dicuz! BBS framework.
- Taught athletes and other employees how to communicate, race, do business, promote the company under the information and international circumstance. Organized and hosted races and training events for professional athletes.

Nanning Xiantong Electronic Commerce LLC.

Nanning, Guangxi, China

Assistant Accountant, Cost Manager Assistant

June 2010 – September 2010

- Recorded journal entries and assisted the accountant and other managers. Analyzed financial statements, and assisted managers for cost management decisions.
- Classified and managed electronic inventories, and matched cost accumulation to inventories.

OTHER ACTIVITIES:

FlightGear DHC6 Twin Otter - https://github.com/bolan/dhc6

Boston, MA

Programmer, Arts Designer, Licensing Negotiator

September 2014 – Present

- Wrote the codes of the most realistic directional gyro instrumentation in Nasal programming language. Wrote a realistic engines and electrical simuation. 3D model and texture mapping.
- Negotiated with other contributors, and eventually released this software under GPLv2.

Northeastern University Cycling Team

Boston, MA

Athlete, Organizer, Volunteer

September 2011 - May 2014

- Organized, hosted riding and race at Eastern Collegiate Cycling Conference.
- Raced bike at Eastern Collegiate Cycling Conference.